Guide to the Administrative Papers of the President George Bugliarello RG.006
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
- Series VI: Publications & Manuscripts
  - subseries A: Publications and Reports
    - "Implications of the Energy Crisis for Engineering Education", 1974 June (Box 42, Folder 48)
    - "C&EN Talks With Dr. George Bugliarello", 1974 June 3 (Box 42, Folder 49)
    - "Towards the Technological University", 1975 September 18 (Box 42, Folder 50)
    - "Social Technology: The Quest for Human Dignity and Machine Efficiency", 1977 July (Box 42, Folder 51)
    - "Risk and Reliability – A Bio-Socio-Technological View", 1978 (Box 42, Folder 52)
    - "Technology and the Environment", 1985 October–1986 April (Box 42, Folder 53)
    - "Institute of Imaging Sciences Five Year Plan", 1986 (Box 42, Folder 54)
    - "Physical and Information Sciences and Engineering", 1989 (Box 42, Folder 55)
    - "Rethinking America's Industry: Challenges for Industry, the Universities & National Policies", 1992 June 4 (Box 42, Folder 56)
    - The Quality – "La Creazione Dell' Universita…", 1993 January-March (Box 42, Folder 57)
    - "Short Course on Security Management", 1993 March 29 (Box 42, Folder 58)
    - "L'Emergere Della Socio-Tecnologica", Undated (Box 42, Folder 59)
    - "A Reflection on Art, Science & Technology", Undated (Box 42, Folder 60)
    - "Report of the President's Commission on the Waste in Human Design", Undated (Box 42, Folder 61)
    - "Synthesis in Engineering: The New Wave" – Notes, Undated (Box 42, Folder 62)
    - "University-Industry Relation, Passion and Rationality", Undated (Box 42, Folder 63)
  - Subseries B: Newspaper Articles
    - Clipping Book – N1-N12, 1975-1991 (Box 42, Folder 64)
    - N6 – New York Times – Flawed Tuition Plan, 1976 November 18 (Box 42, Folder 65)
    - N7 – Social Technology: The Quest for Human Dignity and Machine Efficiency, 1977 July (Box 42, Folder 66)
    - N8 – Detroit Modeling Itself on the Electronics Industry, 1980 December 22 (Box 42, Folder 67)
    - N1, N2, N3, N9, N10, 1975-1985 (Box 42, Folder 68)
    - N18 - "Debate Over Academie's Ties with Industry", 1992 October 21 (Box 42, Folder 69)
  - Subseries C: Research
    - Civil Engineering Education, 1992-1994 (Box 42, Folder 70)
    - Cornell Waste Management, 1989 (Box 42, Folder 71)
    - Earthquake Preparation, 1989-1990 (Box 42, Folder 72)
    - "Science & Technology in Government" – Outline, Undated (Box 42, Folder 73)
  - Subseries D: Notes
    - Miscellaneous, 1979-1993 (Box 42, Folder 74)
    - Handwritten Notes, Undated (Box 42, Folder 75)
    - Handwritten Notes, Undated (Box 42, Folder 76)
    - Handwritten Notes, 1993? (Box 42, Folder 77)
  - Subseries E: Biosoma
    Scope and Content note
    Biosoma, a term coined by George Bugliarello, refers to the interaction between biology, society and machines. This subseries contains manuscripts, drafts, and notes relating to George Bugliarello's research and promotion of the Biosoma paradigm.
    - Biosoma - Draft, 1993 November 30 (Box 42, Folder 78)
    - Biosoma - Draft, Editorial Comments, Undated (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Biosoma: The New Genesis - Correspondence & Edits, 1982 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Biosoma: The New Genesis - Correspondence & Edits, 1982 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Biosoma Figures - Revised, 1979 April (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Biosoma Figures - Revised, 1979 May (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Biosoma - Manuscripts - 1, 1979 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Biosoma - Manuscripts - 2, 1979 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Subseries F: Books
    - i. Written and Edited by George Bugliarello
      - Bugliarello, G. (Ed.) Bioengineering, An Engineering View. San Francisco: San Francisco Press, 1968. 2 copies. (Volume 1)
      - Bugliarello, G. and F. J. Gunther, Computer Systems and Water Resources. Amsterdam: Elsevier Scientific Publishing Company, 1974. (Volume 2)
      - Bugliarello, G. and H.A. Simon, Technology, The Community and The University. Pergamon Press, 1976. (Volume 3)
      - Bugliarello, G. and D. Doner (Eds.) The History and Philosophy of Technology. Chicago: University of Illinois Press, 1979. 2 copies. (Volume 4)
      - Bugliarello, G. (Ed), Urban Security - Engineering the Protection of Our Cities, Polytechnic University, 2003. (Volume 5)
    - ii. Autographed copies
      - Bracewell, Ronald N. The Galactic Club: Intelligent Life in Outerspace. San Francisco: San Francisco Book Company, Inc. 1976. Autographed to Gioia Marconi Braga. (Volume 6)
      - Killian, James R. Jr. Sputnik, Scientists, and Eisenhower: A Memoir of the First Special Assistant to the President of Science and Technology. Massachusetts: The MIT Press. 1977. Autographed to Gioia Marconi Braga. (Volume 7)
      - Dibner, Bern. Immortals of Science: Alessandro Volta and the Electric Battery. New York: Franklin Watts, Inc. 1983. Autographed to Gioia Marconi Braga. (Volume 8)
      - Carassa, Francesco. Il Sogno Dei Gigahertz. Rome: Sarin. 1985. Autographed to George Bugliarello. (Volume 9)
      - Jacobs, Joseph. The Anatomy of an Entrepreneur: Family, Culture and Ethics. San Francisco: ICS Press. 1991. Autographed to George Bugliarello. (Volume 10)
      - Lucky, Robert W. Lucky Strikes...again. New York: IEEE Press. 1993. Autographed to Gioia Marconi Braga. (Volume 11)
    - iii. George Bugliarello Publications Bound Volumes
      - Volume 2, Nos. 12-41, 1962-1967 (Volume 12)
      - Volume 4, Nos. 67-82, 1968-1969 (Volume 13)
      - Volume 5, Nos. 83-103, 1969-1971 (Volume 14)
      - Volume 7, Nos. 123-150, 1975-1981 (Volume 15)
      - Volume 8, Nos. 151-176, 1980-1985 (Volume 16)
      - Volume 9, Nos. 177-219, 1984-1992 (Volume 17)
- Series VII: Correspondence
  This series contains mostly miscellaneous correspondence as well as a collection of business cards collected by George Bugliarello. Frequent correspondents have been separated and given their own folders.
  This series is arranged alphabetically by the last name of the correspondent. The contents of each folder are arranged chronologically.
  - Brademas, John, 1970-1974 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Burkart, Joe, 1980 November-1982 February (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Cardwell, Vivian, undated (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Conti, Jim, 1979 November-1983 October (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Donaruma, Guy, 1980 November–1981 December (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Donaruma, Guy, 1982 December-1983 September (Box 43, Folder 13)
  - Koch, Ed, 1985-1998 (Box 43, Folder 14)
  - Lanier, Lyle, 1981 (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - Maciag, Robert, 1981 April-September (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - Mark, Herman, 1981-1990 (Box 43, Folder 17)
  - Newman, Jeff, 1981 October-1982 February (Box 43, Folder 18)
  - Rafsky, Robert, 1983 June-1984 January (Box 43, Folder 19)
  - Radley, Melanie, 1983 May-October (Box 43, Folder 20)
  - Letters from Significant People, 1966-1967 (Box 43, Folder 21)
  - Technology and Society and Polytechnic, 1975 (Box 43, Folder 22)
  - Taiwan Trip, 1975 (Box 43, Folder 23)
  - Supportive Comments, 1989-1992 (Box 43, Folder 24)
  - Lamme Nomination, 1990 (Box 43, Folder 25)
  - Miscellaneous, 1953 (Box 43, Folder 26)
  - Miscellaneous, 1966 (Box 43, Folder 27)
  - Miscellaneous, 1967 (Box 43, Folder 28)
  - Miscellaneous, 1968 (Box 43, Folder 29)
  - Miscellaneous, 1969 (Box 43, Folder 30)
  - Miscellaneous, 1970 (Box 43, Folder 31)
  - Miscellaneous, 1971 (Box 43, Folder 32)
  - Miscellaneous, 1972 (Box 43, Folder 33)
  - Miscellaneous, 1973 (Box 43, Folder 34)
  - Miscellaneous, 1974 (Box 43, Folder 35)
  - Miscellaneous, 1975 (Box 43, Folder 36)
  - Miscellaneous, 1976 (Box 43, Folder 37)
  - Miscellaneous, 1977 (Box 43, Folder 38)
  - Miscellaneous, 1978 (Box 43, Folder 39)
  - Miscellaneous, 1979 (Box 43, Folder 40)
  - Miscellaneous, 1980 (Box 43, Folder 41)
  - Miscellaneous, 1981 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 1982 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous, 1983 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous, 1984 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous, 1985 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous, 1986 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous, 1987 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous, 1988 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous, 1989 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous, 1990 (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous, January- March 1991, 1991 January- March (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous, April - June 1991, 1991 April - June (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous, July - December 1991, 1991 July - December (Box 44, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous, January - April 1992, 1992 January - April (Box 44, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous, May - December 1992, 1992 May- December (Box 44, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous, January - March 1993, 1993 January-March (Box 44, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous, April - August 1993, 1993 April-August (Box 44, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous, September - November 1993, 1993 September-November (Box 44, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous, December 1993, 1993 December (Box 44, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous, January - February 1994, 1994 January - February (Box 44, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous, March - May 1994, 1994 March - May (Box 44, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous, June - December 1994, 1994 June - December (Box 44, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous, 1995 (Box 44, Folder 23)
  - Miscellaneous, 1996 (Box 44, Folder 24)
  - Miscellaneous, 1997 (Box 44, Folder 25)
  - Miscellaneous, 1998 (Box 44, Folder 26)
  - MIscellaneous, 1999-2000 (Box 44, Folder 27)
  - Miscellaneous, Undated (Box 44, Folder 28)
  - Letters of Recommendation – RESTRICT, 1993 March (Box 44.1, Folder 1)
  - "W" Correspondence, 1990-1992 (Box 44.1, Folder 2)
  - "W" Correspondence, 1990-1992 (Box 44.1, Folder 3)
  - Invitations, 1975-1991 (Box 44.1, Folder 4)
  - Invitations, 1992-1998; Undated (Box 44.1, Folder 5)
  - Business Cards - Loose, undated (Box 44.1, Folder 6)
  - Business Cards – Scrapbook, 1981 November-1984 April (Box 44.1, Folder 7)
  - Business Cards – Scrapbook, 1986 December (Box 44.1, Folder 8)
- Series VIII: Clippings, 1972-1996
  This series is arranged alphabetically by folder title with the excpetion of folders of miscellaneous publications which are arranged chronologically at the end of the series.
  This series contains local, regional and national newspaper and magazine clippings that mention George Bugliarello, Polytechnic, MetroTech or and other topics in engineering and engineering education.
  - Bioengineering, 1972-1992 (Box 44.1, Folder 9)
  - Brooklyn - Atlantic Terminal Rehab, 1984-1985 (Box 44.1, Folder 10)
  - Brooklyn Development, 1983August-1985 August (Box 44.1, Folder 11)
  - George Bugliarello, 1978-1992 (Box 44.1, Folder 12)
  - Brooklyn Newspapers, 1990-1993 (Box 44.1, Folder 13)
  - Brooklyn Newspapers, 1994 (Box 44.1, Folder 14)
  - Brooklyn Newspapers, 1995 (Box 44.1, Folder 15)
  - Brooklyn Newspapers, 1996 (Box 44.1, Folder 16)
  - Long Island Papers - Farmingdale, 1993-1996 (Box 44.1, Folder 17)
  - Long Island Business News, 1995 January-April (Box 44.1, Folder 18)
  - Long Island Business News, 1996 January-October (Box 44.1, Folder 19)
  - New York Newsday, 1992-1996 (Box 44.1, Folder 20)
  - New York and New Jersey Newspapers, 1975-1991 (Box 44.1, Folder 21)
  - Westchester, 1992 November-1994 June (Box 44.1, Folder 22)
  - Westchester, 1994 July-1996 November (Box 44.1, Folder 23)
  - Polytechnic University - Miscellaneous, 1992-1994 (Box 44.1, Folder 24)
  - Polytechnic University - Miscellaneous, 1995 (Box 44.1, Folder 25)
  - Polytechnic University - Miscellaneous, 1996 January-May (Box 44.1, Folder 26)
  - Polytechnic University - Miscellaneous, 1996 June-December (Box 44.1, Folder 27)
  - Italian Newspapers, 1989-1991 (Box 44.1, Folder 28)
  - Miscellaneous, 1967-2011, undated (Box 44.1, Folder 29)
- Series IX: Photographs, 0 Linear Feet
  Arrangement
  Photographs are arranged into two boxes by size: 4"x6" and smaller are in Box 45 and photographs larger than 4"x6" are in Box 46.
  - Dibner Library Construction, 1990-1992 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Dibner Library Construction, 1990-1992 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Dibner Library Construction, 1990-1992 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Dibner Library Construction, 1990-1992 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Dibner Library Construction, 1990-1992 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Dibner Library Construction, 1990-1992 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Dibner Library Construction - Photographs, 1990-1992 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Dibner Library Construction - Photographs, 1990-1992 (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - George Bugliarello - Commencement and Dibner Library, 1992 (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Commencement, 1975 (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Commencement, 1987 (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Commencement, Misc., 1983-1988 (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - Paul Hallingby's Dinner, 1987 (Box 45, Folder 13)
  - Slovenia with Virginia Bugliarello, 1989 (Box 45, Folder 14)
  - Poly Overnight for New Students ("Club Poly"), 1990s (Box 45, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous, 1992 (Box 45, Folder 16)
  - Raduno Internazionale dei Giuliano-Dalmati, 1993 (Box 45, Folder 17)
  - Brussels, 1997 (Box 45, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous, 1990s, 1991-1999 (Box 45, Folder 19)
  - Vancouver with Dr. Lang, undated (Box 45, Folder 20)
  - Photos from All Day Meeting, undated (Box 45, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 45, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous, 1974 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Commencement, 1974, 1976 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Commencement - Honorary degrees, 1974 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Bombay, 1974 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - National Federation of the Italian-American Society, circa 1974 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Helen Lee, 1975 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Unveiling Ernst Weber's Portrait, 1976 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Alumni Association's 113th Dinner Dance, 1976 (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Eugene and Estelle Kone, 1976 (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous, 1990s (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - Westchester Polytechnic Dinner, 1991 (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Campus Development Plan, 1981 (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - Brooklyn Academy of Music, 1982 (Box 46, Folder 13)
  - Herman Mark and Hans Mark, 1983-1984 (Box 46, Folder 14)
  - Ed Koch, 1984 (Box 46, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous, 1985 (Box 46, Folder 16)
  - Howard Golden, 1985 (Box 46, Folder 17)
  - Rome, 1986 (Box 46, Folder 18)
  - 16th Pacific Congress, Seoul, 1987 (Box 46, Folder 19)
  - National Academy of Engineering, 1987 (Box 46, Folder 20)
  - Governor Mario Cuomo, 1988 (Box 46, Folder 21)
  - Argonne National Laboratory, 1990 (Box 46, Folder 22)
  - Venice, 1990 (Box 46, Folder 23)
  - University of Utah Christmas Party, 1991 (Box 46, Folder 24)
  - Photo and clipping from Paul Bruins, 1992 (Box 46, Folder 25)
  - Instituto Dermopatico Dell'Immacolata, 1992 (Box 46, Folder 26)
  - Mayor Rudolph Guiliani, 1994 (Box 46, Folder 27)
  - Events, 1975-1995 (Box 46, Folder 28)
  - Event, undated (Box 46, Folder 29)
  - Citizen Nyembo, Poly and Zaire, undated (Box 46, Folder 30)
  - Marconi Award, undated (Box 46, Folder 31)
  - MetroTech and Mayor Koch, 1990s (Box 46, Folder 32)
  - Miscellaneous, 1966, Undated (Box 46, Folder 33)
  - Dibner Library - Oversize, 1990 (Box 46.1, Folder 1)
  - Rome - Oversize, 1984 (Box 46.1, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous 1975 - Oversize (Box 46.1, Folder 3)
  - Photo album with clippings and articles, 1951-1960 (Box 46.1, Volume 1)
- Series X: Early Career, 1958-1979
  This series contains materials from George Bugliarello's educational and professional career prior to his appointment as University President in 1973 and includes mostly correspondence from his time as student and research assistant at Massachusetts Institute of Technology (1956-1959), professor at Carnegie Mellon University (1959-1966) and professor and Dean of Engineering at University of Illinois at Chicago Circle (1969-1973).
  This series is arranged semi-chronologically by institution (MIT, Carnegie-Mellon University, and University of Illinois at Chicago Circle).
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology – Sigma Xi Membership, 1958 (Box 46, Folder 34)
  - Carnegie-Mellon University – Correspondence, Publications, 1960-1962 (Box 46, Folder 35)
  - Carnegie-Mellon University – Correspondence, Publications, 1963 (Box 46, Folder 36)
  - Carnegie-Mellon University – Publications- "Health Care Needs and Prototype Plans.." – Project Director, 1968 October 1 (Box 46, Folder 37)
  - Carnegie-Mellon University – Professor T.E. Unny, University of Waterloo – Correspondence, 1969 (Box 46, Folder 38)
  - Carnegie-Mellon University – Dr. Michael H. Weissman – RESTRICT, 1970 September (Box 46, Folder 39)
  - Professor Iraj Zandi – Correspondence, 1970 (Box 46, Folder 40)
  - Dr. R.H.J. Sellin – Correspondence, 1973 June (Box 46, Folder 41)
  - Jane Shaw – McGraw Publications – Correspondence, 1970 November (Box 46, Folder 42)
  - Proposal for a Research Center for Environmental Engineering Systems and Communications – George Bugliarello, 1966 February 1 (Box 46, Folder 43)
  - Professor William M. Siebert – MIT – Correspondence, 1971 June-July (Box 46, Folder 44)
  - Notebook – "Rivers and Harbors (Summary) Geo. Bugliarello – V.A.T.Y., Undated (Box 46, Folder 45)
  - University of Illinois at Chicago Circle – Western Pennsylvania Regional Medical Program, 1969 (Box 46, Folder 46)
  - University of Illinois at Chicago Circle – "U" Miscellaneous, 1969-1970 (Box 46, Folder 47)
  - University of Illinois at Chicago Circle – "W" Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1969-1973 (Box 46, Folder 48)
  - University of Illinois at Chicago Circle – University of Utah International Symposium on Human Ecology, 1970 (Box 46, Folder 49)
  - University of Illinois at Chicago Circle – Science Magazine, 1970 August (Box 46, Folder 50)
  - University of Illinois at Chicago Circle – Brian Guy Rice – RESTRICT, 1970-1973 (Box 46, Folder 51)
  - University of Illinois at Chicago Circle – George Yanizeski, 1971 (Box 46, Folder 52)
  - University of Illinois at Chicago Circle – Richmond College, Consulting committee, 1971 (Box 46, Folder 53)
  - University of Illinois at Chicago Circle – Richmond College, Consulting Committee – Syllabi, 1971 (Box 46, Folder 54)
  - University of Illinois at Chicago Circle – Office of Business Affairs – Salaries – RESTRICT, 1971 (Box 46, Folder 55)
  - University of Illinois at Chicago Circle – Engineering Law Seminar, 1971-1972 (Box 46, Folder 56)
  - University of Illinois at Chicago Circle – International Journal of Social Technology – Editorial Advisory Board, 1972-1973 (Box 46, Folder 57)
  - University of Illinois at Chicago Circle – Professor Jeremy Robinson, 1973 June (Box 46, Folder 58)
  - University of Illinois at Chicago Circle – Conference on the Applications of Undergraduate Mathematics – Paper Manuscript, 1973 (Box 46, Folder 59)
  - University of Illinois at Chicago Circle – World Development, 1973 (Box 46, Folder 60)
  - University of Illinois at Chicago Circle – Dr. Noel Vietmeyer, 1973 (Box 46, Folder 61)
  - University of Illinois at Chicago Circle – Correspondence, 1979 (Box 46, Folder 62)
  - University of Illinois at Chicago and Carnegie-Mellon University ("Dean's Personal File"), 1966 May - 1969 October (Box 46, Folder 63)
  - Univerisity of Illinois at Chicago and Carnegie-Mellon University ("Dean's Personal File"), 1969 November- 1971 May (Box 46, Folder 64)
- Series XI: Addendum I
  This addendum to the Administrative Papers of the President George Bugliarello consists of 3 Paige boxes (3.75 linear feet) of unsorted material from the President's office pre-dating George Bugliarello's appointment as University President and includes correspondence, departmental reports, course syllabi, and professors' notes. These documents require additional processing.
  - Pre-Bugliarello - Unsorted, Undated (Box 47)
  - Pre-Bugliarello - Unsorted, Undated (Box 48)
  - Pre-Bugliarello - Unsorted, Undated (Box 49)
- Series XII: Addendum II
  Addendum II is arranged in following subseries that mirror the main series of the collection:
  The arrangement of this series mirrors the arrangement of the previous series in the collection, with subseries as follows:
  MetroTech Center
  Vote of "No Confidence"
  Speeches & Symposia
  Publications & Notes
  Correspondence
  Clippings
  Polytechnic documents
  Memoranda, Newsletters, & Brochures
  MetroTech model
  Scope and Contents
  The additional material in this series was donated to the Poly Archives by Virginia Bugliarello on October 24, 2013. Some of the material was integrated into existing series within the collection, including Speeches & Symposia, Publications & Manuscripts, Correspondence, Clippings, and Photographs. The remainder of the additional material, which could not be integrated due to physical limitations, is in Addendum II.
  Virginia Bugliarello's donation letter for this additional material is in the first box (Box 50) of Addendum II.
  - Subseries A: MetroTech Center, 1984-2004
    - Donation letter to Virginia Bugliarello, 2013 October 24 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence- George Bugliarello, 1984-1989 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence- MetroTech and donations, 1978-1998 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Speeches- Bugliarello, 1989 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - MetroTech proposal, agreements, and fact sheet, 1989-2007 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - MetroTech golden shovel invitation, 1989 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - MetroTech publications, 1992-1999 (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - N.Y. Building Congress Leadership Awards and Park Ranking Index, 1993 (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - MetroTech Case Study, 2004 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - Notes- MetroTech: NY Response to Silicon Valley, undated (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - MetroTech and Tenopolis, 1989-1990 (Box 50, Folder 11)
    - Clippings- MetroTech, 1989-1997 (Box 50, Folder 12)
    - Clippings- Oversize, 1985-1990 (Box 50, Folder 13)
    - Newspapers, 1982-1989 (Box 50, Folder 14)
  - Subseries B: Vote of "No Confidence", 1989
    The folders follow the arrangement of the papers within an envelope labeled, "Vote of 'no confidence' 1989."
    - "A Caution on Unions", 1975 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1989 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Tuition Increase- Commentary and reports, 1989 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - "Resolution", undated (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Memoranda- Members of the Faculty and the Corporation, 1989 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - George Bugliarello's Remarks and Annual Report, 1988 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence- Regarding Governor Carey, 1974 (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Subseries C: Speeches & Symposia
    - Commencement- First Year for Polytechnic Institute of New York (PINY), 1974 (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - Oral Statement by George Bugliarello before the Subcommittee on HUD, 1989 May 4 (Box 51, Folder 9)
    - Caledonian Hospital, 1989 June 2 (Box 51, Folder 10)
    - The Reward of Innovation, 1990 January 5 (Box 51, Folder 11)
    - Commencement Address, Milwaukee School of Engineering, 1991 November 23 (Box 51, Folder 12)
    - Confidential: I.O.R.C. Position Paper (draft, by Bugliarello), circa 1975 (Box 51, Folder 13)
    - Regional Role of Engineering College Conference, 1973 (Box 51, Folder 14)
    - Cornell Seminar, undated (Box 51, Folder 15)
    - Introduction to Newcomen Society, 1975 September 18 (Box 51, Folder 16)
    - Interview with Jeff Newman, 1983 (Box 51, Folder 17)
    - Inauguration Speech Materials, 1955-1974 (Box 51, Folder 18)
    - Humanity 3000: Symposium No. 1 Proceedings, 2000 (Box 51, Folder 19)
    - The University: How Neutral is Neutral?, 1975 January 26 (Box 51, Folder 20)
    - Third Annual Clinical Engineering Symposium and Technical Exhibition, 1987 October 7-9 (Box 51, Folder 21)
    - Speech notes, 1973, 1973; undated (Box 51, Folder 22)
    - Speech notes, undated (Box 51, Folder 23)
  - Subseries D: Publications & Notes
    - L'Aerazione dello Stramazzo Tipo, 1951 (Box 51, Folder 24)
    - The Peripheral Plasma Layer in Pulsatile Flow in Hollow Glass Fibers, 1969 (Box 51, Folder 25)
    - The New Engineering Education, 1973 (Box 51, Folder 26)